Yin-Chung (Lloyd) Huang

148 Jilin Road, Luzhu District, Taoyuan City 338, Taiwan (R.O.C.) r09623007@ntu.edu.tw • +886-905161023

PROFILE

Passionate graduate student with strong chemistry and statistic backgrounds. Held a specific domain knowledge in soil science and involved in multidisciplinary study including mineralogy, machine learning, and remote sensing. Experienced in seminar presentation and assisted teaching lecture for more than two semesters. Aimed to apply spectroscopy and pedology knowledge to solve biogeochemical problems. The ambition is demonstrated by peer-reviewed publications, distinguished academic performance and extracurricular experience.

EDUCATION

National Taiwan University (NTU)

Master of Science in Agricultural Chemistry

Sept. 2020 – June 2022 Taipei, Taiwan

- GPA 4.29/4.30
- Thesis: Characterization of podzolic soils using proximal soil sensing in subtropical subalpine forests

National Taiwan University

Sept. 2019 - Feb. 2022

Biological Statistics Program

- Completed 20 designated credits, including Advanced Statistics, Applied Linear Algebra, Experimental Design, Artificial Neural Networks, and Spatial Analysis

National Taiwan University

Sept. 2017 – June 2020

Taipei, Taiwan

- GPA 4.24/4.30
- Rank 1/55 (summa cum laude)

Bachelor of Science in Agricultural Chemistry

PUBLICATION

Huang, Y.C. and Hseu, Z.Y. 2021. Silicon availability in relation to soil properties in Inceptisols on uncultivated lands and paddy fields in Taiwan. Geoderma Regional, e00406. (SCI, IF = 2.807)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Soil Survey and Remediation Lab

July 2017 – Present

- Explored the application of portable X-ray fluorescence and Vis/NIR/SWIR spectroradiometers on elucidating soil genesis process
- Investigated the differentiation of podzolic soils in subalpine forests in Taiwan using selective extraction, micromorphology, and multivariate statistics
- Analyzed the distribution of Silicon availability and its difference in forest soils and paddy fields of Taiwan
- Carried out physical and chemical analysis on the soils from an archeological site for the department of Anthropology, NTU

AWARDS & HONORS

Honorable Mention for Academic Thesis Competition

Annual Meeting of the Geography Society of China

May 2021

Honorable Mention for Poster Competition

Annual Meeting of the Chinese Society of Soil and Fertilizer Sciences

Nov. 2020

Dean's List Award (Academic Excellence Award)

Top 5% of class in semester

Oct. 2020 Oct. & Apr. 2019

- Demonstrated diligence on every subject

Oct. & Apr. 2018

- Completed all credits with outstanding grades

Oct. & Apr. 2017

July 2019 – June 2022

Hsin Tian Kong Long-term Scholarship

1500 USD each semester

- Acquired financial support from the Cultural and Educational Foundation of the largest temple in Taiwan

Pedometric Webinar

June 2021 Oral presentation Virtual

- Webinar held by the Pedometrics commission of the International Union of Soil Sciences (IUSS)
- Topic: Characterization of podzolic soils using digital morphometrics in a subtropical subalpine forest of Taiwan

Annual Meeting of the Geography Society of China

May 2021

Virtual

Oral presentation

Topic: Characterization of podzolic soils in Shanlinshi using digital soil morphometrics

Annual Meeting of the Chinese Society of Soil and Fertilizer Sciences

Nov. 2020

Poster presentation

Taichung, Taiwan

- Topic: Using Vis-NIR spectroscopy and pXRF to pedogenesis
- Presented research progress of a collaborative project with the Department of Geology, NTU

Conference of the East and Southeast Asia Federation of Soil Science **Societies**

Nov. 2019 Taipei, Taiwan

Oral presentation

Topic: Silicon availability and its relation to other properties of soils in Taiwan

Joint Seminar on Environmental Ecology and Restoration

Aug. 2018

Oral presentation

Hakodate, Japan

- Joint seminar between NTU and Ishikawa Prefectural University
- Topic: Element composition of the colluvial soils at an archeological site from Linkou terrace, Taiwan
- Presented research progress of a collaborative project with the Department of Anthropology, NTU

SKILLS

Computer Programming

R & Python

Laboratory Instruments

- Field-portable Vis/NIR/SWIR spectroradiometers (ASD FieldSpec 3)
- Portable X-ray fluorescence spectroscopy (Olympus DELTA Premium pXRF)
- Atomic absorption spectroscopy
- X-ray diffraction

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Soil Science Lab (2020, 2021)

Sept. 2021 - Jan. 2022

Teaching assistant

Sept. 2020 – Jan. 2021

- Organized weekly soil science lab lecture
- Delivered lectures on soil science and statistics

EXTRACURRICULAR EXPERIENCE

NTU Agricultural Chemistry Workshop (For Highschool Students)

July 2019

Director of Academic Department

Taipei, Taiwan

- Organized seminar on the topic of "The Merits and Sins of Paraquat"
- Delivered lectures on soil analysis & soil chemistry

Overseas Community Affairs Council (OCAC, ROC)

July 2018

Participator of OCAC Youth Bridge Program

London, UK

- Visited Taipei Representative Office (TRO) in the UK
- Discussed with the Representative (Ambassador) on the topic of youth education

Harvard World Model United Nations (MUN) 2017

Delegate of Iraq from NTU MUN Society

Mar. 2017 Montreal, Canada

- Committee: World Health Organization (WHO) Topic: Reforming the Global Pharmaceutical Industry
- Contributed to the Draft Resolution that was adopted by the committee